Guide to the New York City Central Labor Council Photographs PHOTOS 020
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IV: Events, 1963-1991
  - Subseries B: Awards
    - Randolph, Philip: In Memorium, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 197)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art: Chinese Garden Court, Jan 1980 (Box 7, Folder 198)
    - Centennial Labor Celebration, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 199)
    - Meany Public School, circa 1981, undated (Box 7, Folder 200)
    - Adult Learning, Mar 17, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 201)
    - Donahue Speaks, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 202)
    - Mann, Michael: Tribute, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 203)
    - Medical Labor Seminar, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 204)
    - Statue of Liberty, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 205)
- Series V: Chronological
  Series V: Chronological, 1940s-1990s, is composed of general photographs accumulated by the New York City Central Labor Council over a period of approximately fifty years.
  - 1940s, 1940s, undated (Box 7, Folder 206)
  - [1940s], circa 1940s, undated (Box 7, Folder 207)
  - 1950s, 1950s, undated (Box 7, Folder 208)
  - [1950s], circa 1950s, undated (Box 7, Folder 209)
  - 1960s, 1960s, undated (Box 7, Folder 210)
  - [1960s], circa 1960s, undated (Box 7, Folder 211)
  - [1960s], circa 1960s, undated (Box 8, Folder 212)
  - 1970s, undated (Box 8, Folder 213)
  - Undated (Box 8, Folder 214)
  - [1970s], circa 1970s, undated (Box 8, Folder 215)
  - [1970s], circa 1970s, undated (Box 8, Folder 216)
  - [1970s], circa 1970s, undated (Box 8, Folder 217)
  - 1980s, 1980s, undated (Box 9, Folder 218)
  - [1980s], circa 1980s, undated (Box 9, Folder 219)
  - [1980s], circa 1980s, undated (Box 9, Folder 220)
  - 1990s, 1990s, undated (Box 9, Folder 221)
- Series VI: Portraits and Individuals, 1940s-1990s
  Series VI: Portraits/Individuals, undated, contains nearly comprehensive photographic documentation of New York City Central Labor Council's leadership and honorees. This series is organized into individual folders for particularly prominent and/or well-documented people, and also an alphabetic sequence ordered by surname for lesser-known individuals.
  - Avrutin, Harry, undated (Box 9, Folder 222)
  - General Portraits: "A", undated (Box 9, Folder 223)
  - Beame, Mayor Abraham, undated (Box 9, Folder 224)
  - Bowe, William, undated (Box 9, Folder 225)
  - General Portraits: "B", undated (Box 9, Folder 226)
  - Chavez, Caesar, undated (Box 9, Folder 227)
  - General Portraits: "C", undated (Box 9, Folder 228)
  - Davis, Sammy, Jr., undated (Box 9, Folder 229)
  - Dubinsky, David, undated (Box 9, Folder 230)
  - Durst, David, undated (Box 9, Folder 231)
  - General Portraits: "D" and "E", undated (Box 9, Folder 232)
  - Feldman, Sandra, undated (Box 9, Folder 233)
  - General Portraits: "F", undated (Box 9, Folder 234)
  - Garrahan, Charles, undated (Box 9, Folder 235)
  - Guinan, Matthew, undated (Box 9, Folder 236)
  - General Portraits: "G", undated (Box 9, Folder 237)
  - General Portraits: "H", undated (Box 9, Folder 238)
  - Iushewitz, Morris, undated (Box 9, Folder 239)
  - General Portraits: "I" and "J", undated (Box 9, Folder 240)
  - Kennedy, Robert F., undated (Box 10, Folder 241)
  - King, Martin Luther, Jr., undated (Box 10, Folder 242)
  - General Portraits: "K", undated (Box 10, Folder 243)
  - Lawe, John, undated (Box 10, Folder 244)
  - Lewis, John L. (Displayed for Labor Day Parade), Sep 1961 (Flat-file 6, Drawer 15)
  - General Portraits: "L", undated (Box 10, Folder 245)
  - Meany, George, undated (Box 10, Folder 246)
  - General Portraits: "M", undated (Box 10, Folder 247)
  - General Portraits: "N", undated (Box 10, Folder 248)
  - General Portraits: "O", undated (Box 10, Folder 249)
  - Pollack, Cecilia (New York City Teachers Union), undated (Box 10, Folder 250)
  - Potofsky, Jacob, undated (Box 10, Folder 251)
  - General Portraits: "P", undated (Box 10, Folder 252)
  - Quill, Michael, undated (Box 10, Folder 253)
  - Quinn, James, undated (Box 10, Folder 254)
  - Randolph, Philip A.: Portraits, undated (Box 10, Folder 255)
  - Randolph, Philip A.: Day, undated (Box 10, Folder 256)
  - Randolph, Philip A.: Week, undated (Box 10, Folder 257)
  - Randolph, Philip A.: 50th Anniversary Sleeping Car Porters, undated (Box 10, Folder 258)
  - Roberts, Lillian, undated (Box 10, Folder 259)
  - Reuther, Walter, undated (Box 10, Folder 260)
  - General Portraits: "Q" and "R", undated (Box 10, Folder 261)
  - Shanker, Albert, undated (Box 10, Folder 262)
  - Solzhenitsyn, A., undated (Box 10, Folder 263)
  - Stokowski, Leopold, undated (Box 10, Folder 264)
  - Sullivan, Dave, undated (Box 10, Folder 265)
  - Sweeney, John, undated (Box 10, Folder 266)
  - General Portraits: "S", undated (Box 10, Folder 267)
  - Toohy, Ed, undated (Box 10, Folder 268)
  - Van Arsdale, Harry, Jr., undated (Box 10, Folder 269)
  - Van Arsdale, Harry, Jr., undated (Box 10, Folder 270)
  - Van Arsdale, Harry, Jr., undated (Box 11, Folder 271)
  - Van Arsdale, Thomas, undated (Box 11, Folder 272)
  - General Portraits: "T" - "V", undated (Box 11, Folder 273)
  - General Portraits: "W" - "Z", undated (Box 11, Folder 274)
  - General Portraits: Mounted (Identified), undated (Box 11, Folder 275)
  - General Portraits: Mounted (Unidentified), undated (Box 11, Folder 276)
  - General Portraits (Unidentified), undated (Box 11, Folder 277)
- Series VII: Parades, 1948-1997
  Series VII: Parades, 1948-1997, documents the New York City Easter Parade, Labor Day Parade, May Day Parade, and Solidarity Day Parade. A majority of the photographs contained within this series are of the Labor Day Parade in its various manifestations between the 1960s and early 1990s.
  - Subseries A: Easter
    - Easter Parade, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 278)
  - Subseries B: Labor Day
    - Labor Day Parade, undated (Box 11, Folder 279)
    - Labor Day Parade, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 280)
    - Labor Day Parade, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 281)
    - Labor Day Parade, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 282)
    - Labor Day Parade: Committee Meetings, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 283)
    - Labor Day Parade, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 284)
    - Labor Day Parade, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 285)
    - Labor Day Parade, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 286)
    - Labor Day Parade, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 287)
    - Labor Day Parade, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 288)
    - Labor Day Parade, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 289)
    - Labor Day Parade, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 290)
    - Labor Day Parade, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 291)
    - Labor Day Parade, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 292)
    - Labor Day Parade, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 293)
    - Labor Day Parade, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 294)
    - Labor Day Parade, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 295)
    - Labor Day Parade, circa 1993 (Box 13, Folder 296)
    - Labor Day Parade, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 297)
    - Labor Day Parade, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 298)
    - Labor Day Parade and Breakfast (Tom Matthews, photographer), 1996 (Box 14, Folder 299)
    - Labor Day Parade (Al Eckman, photographer), 1997 (Box 14, Folder 300)
  - Subseries C: May Day, undated
    - May Day Parade, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 301)
  - Subseries D: St. Patrick's Day
    - St. Patrick's Day Parade, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 302)
    - St. Patrick's Day Parade, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 303)
  - Subseries E: Solidarity Day, 1982-1983
    - Solidarity Day, Jan 30, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 304)
    - Solidarity Day Parade Meeting, Aug 25, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 305)
- Series VIII: Demonstrations, 1965-1984
  Series VIII: Demonstrations, 1965-1984, is comprised of photographic documentation of demonstrations led by numerous organizations or agencies in New York City. Particularly well-represented in this series are demonstrations by the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union, The National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians, and the Transport Workers Union, among others.
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 14, Folder 306)
  - Actors Equity, Contra UNESCO, Jan 1975 (Box 14, Folder 307)
  - Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union: Against Clothing Imports, undated (Box 14, Folder 308)
  - Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union: Farah, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 309)
  - Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union: Farah, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 310)
  - Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union: J. P. Stevens, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 311)
  - Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union: J. P. Stevens, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 312)
  - Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union: J. P. Stevens, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 313)
  - Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union: Occupational Safety & Health Administration, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 314)
  - American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees: Lincoln Hospital, undated (Box 14, Folder 315)
  - American Federation of Teachers: Newark Teachers Union, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 316)
  - American Federation of Teachers: Christ the King, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 317)
  - American Federation of Television and Radio Artists Wins, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 318)
  - American Guild of Musical Artists Strike Against New York Philharmonic, undated (Box 15, Folder 319)
  - American Postal Workers Union, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 320)
  - Amalgamated Transit Union: Bus Drivers, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 321)
  - Amalgamated Transit Union: Greyhound, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 322)
  - Bakery and Confectionary Workers, undated (Box 15, Folder 323)
  - Buildings and Construction Trade Council, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 324)
  - Civil Rights Rallies, undated (Box 15, Folder 325)
  - Communications Workers of America, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 326)
  - Communications Workers of America: AT&T, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 327)
  - Department Store and Retail Workers, undated (Box 15, Folder 328)
  - Engineering and Professional Guild Local 66, undated (Box 15, Folder 329)
  - Hospital Workers, undated (Box 15, Folder 330)
  - Hotel and Restaurant Workers, undated (Box 15, Folder 331)
  - International Association of Machinists & Aerospace Workers: Colt Menasco, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 332)
  - International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees: ABC, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 333)
  - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Local 3, undated (Box 15, Folder 334)
  - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers: CBS, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 335)
  - International Union of Electrical Workers Local 463, undated (Box 15, Folder 336)
  - International Union of Electrical Workers: Anaconda, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 337)
  - International Union of Electrical Workers: General Electric, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 338)
  - Laborers' International Union: Local 1207, undated (Box 15, Folder 339)
  - Free Lillian Roberts, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 340)
  - Medicare, undated (Box 15, Folder 341)
  - Mondale Rally, undated (Box 15, Folder 342)
  - National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians: ABC Disney, undated (Box 15, Folder 343)
  - National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians: National Black Network Strike, undated (Box 15, Folder 344)
  - National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians: NBC, undated (Box 15, Folder 345)
  - National Association of Letter Carriers, Feb 1979 (Box 15, Folder 346)
  - Nathans, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 347)
  - New Yorkers United Day, undated (Box 15, Folder 348)
  - New York Hotel and Motel Trades Council, undated (Box 16, Folder 349)
  - Newspaper Guild: New York Strike, circa 1966 (Box 16, Folder 350)
  - Newspaper Guild: New York Post, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 351)
  - Office and Professional Employees International Union: Group Health Incorporated (GHI), 1976 (Box 16, Folder 352)
  - Port Authority Transit Corporation, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 353)
  - Paramutual Clerks: Aqueduct, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 354)
  - Police and Firefighters, undated (Box 16, Folder 355)
  - Prices, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 356)
  - Professional Staff Congress, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 357)
  - Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union: Macy's, Abraham & Straus, Lord and Taylor, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 358)
  - Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union: District 65: Bloomingdales, undated (Box 16, Folder 359)
  - Screen Actors Guild and American Federation of Television & Radio Artists, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 360)
  - Service Employees International Union: Carson Park Hospital, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 361)
  - Service Employees International Union: Picket, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 362)
  - Shanker, Albert: Jailing, circa 1967-1968 (Box 16, Folder 363)
  - Shoe Workers, undated (Box 16, Folder 364)
  - Social Security Rally, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 365)
  - Soviet Jewry, undated (Box 16, Folder 366)
  - Taxi Drivers, undated (Box 16, Folder 367)
  - Taxi Drivers: Madison Square Garden Rally, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 368)
  - Teachers, Professors, and Support Staff, undated (Box 16, Folder 369)
  - Textile Workers, undated (Box 16, Folder 370)
  - Transport Workers Union: Flight Attendants, undated (Box 16, Folder 371)
  - Transport Workers Union: Transit Rally, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 372)
  - Transport Workers Union: Continental Airlines and Professional Air Traffic Controllers Organization, 1981, 1984, undated (Box 16, Folder 375)
  - Transport Workers Union: Argentine Airlines, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 373)
  - Transport Workers Union: Eastern Airlines, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 374)
  - New York Typographical Union No.6, undated (Box 16, Folder 376)
  - United Farm Workers: Hunter College Rally, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 377)
  - United Farm Workers: Boycott, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 378)
  - United Farm Workers of America: LA-Z-BOY Chair, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 379)
- Series IX: Electoral Politics
  Series IX: Electoral Politics, 1949-1978, documents the New York City Central Labor Council's multiple registration drives as well as its participation in political campaigns of varied scale, most notably that of President Jimmy Carter.
  - Subseries A: Voter Registration
    - Registration Drive, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 380)
    - Registration Drive, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 381)
    - Registration Drive, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 382)
  - Subseries B: Election Campaigns
    - Campaign: United Labor Committee, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 383)
    - Campaign: Stevenson, Oct 10, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 384)
    - Campaign: Harrison for New York State Governor, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 385)
    - Campaign: Wagner Primary, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 386)
    - Elections, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 387)
    - Campaign: Carter Train, Penn Station, Sep 20, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 388)
    - Elections, Nov 5, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 389)
    - Carter, President Jimmy: City Hall, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 390)
    - Elections: New York Gubernatorial, October 1978 (Box 17, Folder 391)
- Series X: Community Services, 1963-1977, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  Series X: Community Services, 1963-1977, documents the activities of the New York City Central Labor Council's Community Services Committee. The Community Services Committee, founded in 1953, achieved many of its goals through the formation of various subcommittees, such as the Subcommittee on Aging and the Rehabilitation Council. Under a grant from the Office of Vocational Rehabilitation and the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, the Rehabilitation Council was formed in 1963, and has come to be known as the "Social Service Arm of the Trade Union Movement."
  - Community Services, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Community Services, 1963, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Community Services, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Community Services, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Community Services, 1965, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Community Services, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Community Services, 1966, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Community Services, 1967, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Community Services, April 1967 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Community Services, 1967, undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Community Services, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Community Services, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Community Services, 1968, undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Community Services, April 1969 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Community Services, April 1969 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Community Services, 1969, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Community Services, 1970, undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Community Services, April 1970 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Community Services, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Community Services, 1971, undated (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Community Services, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Community Services, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Community Services, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Community Services, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Community Services, 1973, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Community Services, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Community Services, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Community Services, 1976, undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Community Services, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Community Services, 1977, undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Community Services, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Series XI: Other Organizations, 1962-1979
  Series XI: Other Organizations, 1962-1979, contains photographic documentation of various groups with which the Central Labor Council had cause to interact. Included in this series are photographs of a convention held by the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; the National Committee for Labor Israel; and the Union Label and Service Trades. Particularly well-represented in this series are the United Farm Workers.
  - Convention: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 392)
  - Installation: Local 1199, May 1972 (Box 17, Folder 393)
  - National Committee for Labor Israel, undated (Box 17, Folder 394)
  - Union Label and Service Trades, undated (Box 17, Folder 395)
  - Cavalcade of Skills: Union Label and Service Trades, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 396)
  - United Farm Workers, undated (Box 17, Folder 397)
  - United Farm Workers: Cesar Chavez Reception, Dec 19, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 398)
  - United Farm Workers Day, May 10, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 399)
  - United Farm Workers: City Hall, Jun 25, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 400)
- Series XII: Copy Negatives, 1981-1983
  Series XII: Copy Negatives, 1981-1983, contains negatives of photographs shot at the New York City Labor Day Parade, as well as the negatives from several portraits of Central Labor Council leaders.
  - Labor Day Parade: Grand Marshall Lane shakes hands w/ Cardinal in front of St. Patrick's Cathedral, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 401)
  - Labor Day Parade: New York State Gubernational Candidate Mario Cuomo and his wife, Matilda, on reviewing stand, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 402)
  - Labor Day Parade: New York Gubernational Candidate, Mario Cuomo, and his wife, marching in Parade, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 403)
  - Labor Day Parade: Grand Marshall Sandy Feldman and others march; [Lane Kirkland] addresses crowd, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 404)
  - Portraits: "B" (Bahr, Morton), undated (Box 17, Folder 405)
  - Portraits: "O" (O'Brien, Peter), undated (Box 17, Folder 406)
  - Portraits: Randolph, A. Philip, undated (Box 17, Folder 407)
  - Portraits: Shanker, Albert, undated (Box 17, Folder 408)
  - Portraits: Sweeney, John, undated (Box 17, Folder 409)
  - General Unidentified, undated (Box 17, Folder 410)
- Series XIII: Oversized Prints
  - Oversized Prints (Flat-file 6, Drawer 14, Box XOS002, Folder 1, Box OS002)
  - Portrait: McLaughlin, Brain; John Sweeney, Ted Jacobsen and Unidentified, Sep 1, 2004 (Flat-file 1, Drawer 13)
- Series XIV: Unprocessed (Box 22, Box 28, Box 23, Box 24, Box 25, Box 26, Box 27)